（東雲(しののめ)なの）はあっ
（阪本(さかもと)）ん？
Wow!
うわーあ
キラキラしてます
It's sparkling!
Hey, what are you doing?
（阪本）おい　何やってんだ？
あっ あっ 阪本さん
Oh, Sakamoto-san.
Wait!
あっ そっち行っちゃダメです
Don't go over there!
（なの）阪本さん
最近 抜け毛ひどいでしょ？
Sakamoto-san, your shedding has become worse these past few days.
You'll get fur on it.
毛が付いちゃいますから
What is it, girl?
（阪本）
なんだ 娘 邪魔者扱いか？
Am I being a bother?
I need to change, so please step outside for a moment.
着替えますので
ちょっと出ててください
Nichijou 56
フン
きゃーあっ！
Sakamoto-san, please look at this!
阪本さん  見てください！
ピッタリです
It's a perfect fit!
（阪本）
そ… そりゃあ 娘に合わせて
作ってもらったんだから―
Well, of course!
It was made just for you, so of course it would fit!
当たり前だろ
どうです？
How is it?
（阪本）
まあ 似合ってんじゃねえのか？
Well, it looks good.
（なの）そうじゃなくって
そうじゃなくって！
Not like that, not like that!
ふ… 普通の 女の子っぽく―
Do I look...
...like a normal girl?
見えますか？
Well, I guess you look like any other girl.
（阪本）
まあ そこらの娘と一緒だな
Sakamoto-san!
阪本さーん
Whoa!
（阪本）おお おお おっと
（なの）好きです
I love you so much, Sakamoto-san!
（なの）阪本さん　大好き！
（阪本）おお おお おお おおっ
（なの）あっ！ 毛が付いちゃう
（阪本）どうしたいんだ お前は
Oh, you'll get fur on it.
What's with you?
It's school!
（なの）学校ですよ　学校！
I might be able to make some friends!
友達とか できちゃうかも
しれないんですよ？
There's no flow to this conversation!
（阪本）
会話になってねえぞ！
Hey, Nano-chan, do you want to go eat ice cream on the way home?
そうだ！ なのちゃん
学校の帰りに
アイスクリーム食べてかない？
あっ ええ
行きます 行きます
Yes, I'll go.
Then, after that, want to go sing karaoke?
じゃあ そのあと
カラオケもしてく？
えっ？ ええ  でも 私…
Oh, but... I've never been to one before.
行ったことないです
I'll teach you how, so let's all go together!
私が教えてあげる
みんなで行こうよ
Oh, well, then...
あっ は… はい　じゃあ
Things like that!
（なの）とかですよ
（阪本）うおーと うっ
（はかせ）おはよう　なの
（なの）あっ！ はかせ
Good morning, Nano.
Oh, Professor!
Good morning!
（なの）おはようございます
Please look at this, Professor!
見てください はかせ！
How does it look?
どうですか？ 似合ってます？
Does it look good on me?
Um...
（はかせ）うんと
Yeah, it looks cool!
うん　カッコいい！
はああっ はかせ！
Professor!
Those pyjamas look good on you, too, Professor!
はかせも似合ってますよ
このパジャマ
（はかせ）わーい カッコいい？
Are they cool?
（なの）はかせ  カッコいいです！
（はかせ）ふふん
Professor, you're very cool!
（阪本）
いつもと同じじゃねえか
Isn't it the same as every other day?
Sakamoto!
（はかせ）阪本
（阪本）ううっ
（はかせ）阪本もカッコいい
（阪本）お前もか
Sakamoto's cool, too!
Handkerchief, check; student card, check;
（なの）
ハンカチよし 学生証よし
textbooks, check; notebook, check; pencil box, check;
教科書よし ノートよし
筆箱よし
mechanical pencils, check; pencil lead, check!
シャーペンよし
シャーペンの芯よし …っと
All right.
よし 忘れ物なし！
I didn't forget anything.
はかせ？
Professor?
忘れ物あるよ
You forgot something.
え？ 何ですか？ えっと…
Huh?
What is it?
When you get hungry...
おなかがすいたら？
Oh!
Snickers!
（はかせ）スニッカーズ！
（なの）はかせ！
Professor!
I've prepared breakfast and lunch and put them both in the kitchen,
（なの）台所に 朝ごはんと
お昼ごはん用意しておいたので―
so please eat them.
食べてくださいね
I'll also bring in the laundry when I get back,
あと 洗濯物は 帰ってきたら
取り込むので―
so you don't have to do anything.
何もしなくて大丈夫です
ねえ  学校って
何時くらいに終わるの？
Hey, about what time does school end?
Around 3:30, I guess.
３時半くらいですかね？
I need to do some shopping for dinner on the way back,
帰りに 夕飯の
買い物してくるので―
so I'll probably be home around five.
家に戻るのは５時くらいかと
（はかせ）あっ ５時
Five.
Huh, didn't I already tell you?
あれ？ 言ってませんでしたっけ？
Five is already night time.
（はかせ）５時って もう 夜だよ
Yes, but it's because of school.
はい　でも 学校ですから
じゃあ いって…
Well, I'm going no-
Um, Professor?
あの はかせ？
I changed my mind!
やっぱ 行っちゃダメ！
What?
Just a bit earlier, you said I could go!
さっき 行ってもいいって
言ったじゃないですか
I don't want you to go!
行っちゃヤダ！
そんなあ　遅刻しちゃいますよ
No way!
I'm going to be late!
Please give me back my bag!
バッグ返してください
Ah, my left hand!
左手！
Stop being unreasonable!
（阪本）おい ガキ！
聞き分けのないことを言うな！
Professor...
はかせ
Then how about this?
じゃあ こうしましょ
For dinner tonight, I'll make Professor's favourite omelette rice!
今日の晩ごはんは はかせの好きな
オムライスにします
えっと それと 帰りに
サメカステラも買ってきます
And on my way back, I'll buy some shark castella!
ええっ じゃあ
I'll also add some strawberry juice.
じゃあ イチゴジュースも
付けちゃいます
じゃあ…
Well...
Well?
じゃあ？
The Akutagawa Prize, too?
芥川(あくたがわ)賞も？
（なの）そ… そりゃ無理だあ！
T-That's not possible!
I was worried how that would turn out for a bit,
（なの）一時は
どうなることかと思ったけど
but I'm glad I got Professor to cooperate.
何とか はかせが
折れてくれてよかった
And now, I've taken the first step towards being a regular person.
これで私も 普通の人としての
第一歩を
Crap!
しまった　すっかり忘れてた
I've completely forgot!
The key on my back!
背中のネジ どうしよう
What should I do?
Things that we think are cool!
（長野原(ながのはら)みお･相生祐子(あいおいゆうこ)）
カッコいいと思うもの！
All right.
よーし やっちゃうか！
Let's do it!
Yeah!
（みお･祐子）
おう！ やる気になった先輩！
A motivated senpai!
What should I do?
（なの）どうしよう
It's not like I can come up with an answer,
なんて考えても
答えが出るわけもなく
no matter how much I think about it.
And now I'm here.
とうとう ここまで
来てしまった
And now I'll introduce a transfer student.
（桜井(さくらい)先生）
では ここで転校生を紹介します
東雲さーん
Shinonome-san!
（なの）は… はい！
Yes!
I knew it!
や… やっぱり
みんな ネジ 気にしてる
Everyone noticed my key!
（桜井）はい 東雲さん
自分で名前 書いてくださいね
Shinonome-san, could you write your name?
My key is getting a ton of attention...
ネジ すごい目立ってる
I need to say something about it!
何とか ごまかさないと
My name is Shinonome Nano!
（なの）
しし… 東雲なのっていいます
え… えっと
それでですね あのっ
And you see, this key is...
このネジはですね
その… あの… 実は―
The truth is...
It got stuck in me on the way here!
道中(どうちゅう) 刺さったんです！
Oh no!
（なの）
しまった ドン引かれた
That caused even more attention!
Um, well, you see...
えっ いや ええっとですね
つまり ホントは―
The truth is...
...I was kidding!
ウソです！
Oh no, why am I correcting myself?
（なの）しまった
何 言い直してるんだ
うわあ どうしよう
えーと えーと
What should I do?
It's not like my big toe changes into a USB drive if you turn it...
いや だから…
巻いても親指がＵＳＢとか
そういうロボ的なものではなくて
...or anything robotic like that!
It's no good!
（なの）もうダメだあ！
Fortune Telling
Tell me tomorrow's weather!
（祐子）
♪ あした 天気になーあれっ
Nichijou 57
Hey, Sekiguchi.
（大工健三郎(だいくけんざぶろう)）なあ 関口(せきぐち)
Go
Soccer
Club
Don't just sit there reading books.
本ばっかり読んでないで遊ぼうぜ
Play something with me!
Go Soccer Club - Club President
Daiku Kenzaburou
2nd Year
I even bought The Game of Life...
せっかく 人生ゲーム
買ってきたんだしさ
Go Soccer Club - Club Member
Sekiguchi Yuria
1st Year
ああ 暇だなあ
I'm so bored.
Since we're the Go Soccer Club, maybe I'll solve some Go problems.
囲碁サッカー部だけに
詰め碁でもするかな
囲碁はできないけど
Even if I can't play Go...
（ドアが開く音）
（桜井 誠(まこと)）失礼しまーす
Excuse me.
（誠）あのう ここ
囲碁サッカー部ですよね？
Is this the Go Soccer Club?
Yeah.
（誠）入部 したいんですが
（大工）あっ！
I would like to join.
I'd love for you to!
（大工）大歓迎だ！
What's your name?
君 名前は？
I'm Sakurai Makoto, a first year.
い… １年の桜井誠です
I see!
そうかあ
I'm a second year and the president of this club, Daiku Kenzaburou!
俺は２年で部長の
大工健三郎
And this is another first year, Sekiguchi-kun.
こっちは １年の関口君だ
（ユリア）あっ
（誠）エヘヘ
Well, sit down!
（大工）まあまあ 座ってくれよ
（誠）ああ はい
Ah, sure.
So, what do you want to do?
…で どうする？
人生ゲームでもする？
Want to play Life?
Um, don't you practise?
あの 練習はしないんですか？
Huh?
For Go Soccer.
囲碁サッカーの
ハハッ 実は
囲碁サッカーていうのは―
Actually, Go Soccer is just something that I made up.
俺が作った
伝説上の部活なんだ
We don't actually do that.
そんな競技はホントはなくて―
It's more of a recreational club where everyone can have fun.
基本は みんなで
楽しく遊ぼうっていう―
まあ いわば
レクリエーション部だな
I see...
But I was in the Go Soccer Club back in middle school.
でも俺 中学のとき
囲碁サッカー部だったりして
Huh?
I didn't know there was a Go Soccer Club at this school!
この学校に 囲碁サッカー部
あったなんて 知りませんでした
You know, there were those large banners for it,
ほら この前 校舎に
垂れ幕が掛かってて―
and that's how I found out.
それで気付いたんですよ
I was actually the MVP in middle school!
実は俺 中学ＭＶＰだったりして
Curious
（桜井）うっ ハアッ
うっ  し… 東雲さん
Shinonome-san!
Oh, yes?!
はっ はい！
あ… あの どうしても
気になっちゃって
Um, it has really been bugging me, but...
その 背中の…
...the thing on your back...
Um, well, you see...
ええ？ あっ えと
（なの）いや あの その…
（桜井）ああ えと あの…
Nichijou 57.5
（ユリア）あのう
Well, what kind of things did you do in the Go Soccer Club?
囲碁サッカー部って―
どんなことするんですか？
（誠）うーん
口で説明するのは難しいかな
It's a bit difficult to explain in words...
I'll show you my practise routine.
じゃあ 個人演舞を
お見せしますね
First, lifting.
まずは リフティング
After lifting, Go stones!
リフティングからの―
碁石！
And then...
（誠）そして―
After Go stones, One-Man German!
碁石からの　フンッ
１人ジャーマン！
This is it! The Avalanche Joseki!
TL note: "Avalanche Joseki" is a common starting sequence of moves in Go.
これぞ なだれ定石(じょうせき) 三連星！
Three-Star Set!
TL note: "Three-Star Set" is a move that takes the two corners and the middle of one side of the board.
Good heavens...
（大工）何てこった
Go
Soccer
Club
I half-heartedly made this club, and now...
軽い気持ちで作った
部活だったのだが
こりゃあ―
It's become interesting!
面白くなってきやがった
Shoes
（祐子）ハア ハア ハア
ハッ ハウッ！
（犬）アウーン！
（祐子）はっ！
Hey, wait up!
（キヨシ）ちょ 待てよ
What's got into you all of a sudden?
どうしたんだよ　いきなり
どこ行くんだよ バディ！
Where are you going, Buddy?
Word Of The Day
Sakamoto!
阪本！
（阪本）おお おい バカ
ちょっと やめろって
No, wait, idiot!
（はかせ）阪本 阪本！
Stop!
What is it, you ask? It's going around in circles.
Buddy
（祐子）ハア ハア ハア
（バディ）ヘッ ヘッ ヘッ
（祐子）ハア ハア
Nichijou 58
（なの）初日から
あんな大失敗するなんて
I made such a big mistake on the first day.
I bet everyone is thinking I'm strange.
みんな 変な子だって
怪しんでるんだろうなあ
Oh, Nano-chan, you have a bento today, huh?
（みお）
へえ　なのちゃん お弁当なんだ
えっ？ あっ は… はい
Y-Yeah.
That looks delicious.
おいしそうだね
いつも お弁当なの？
Do you always bring a bento?
Yes, I do!
は… はい！ 普通ですので
Because it's normal.
I'll let you see this.
（水上麻衣(みなかみまい)）見せてあげる
あっ カッコいいですね
It's cool,
isn't it?
（祐子）ハア ハア
Mio-chan, sorry for the wait.
みおちゃん おまたせ
You're so slow, Yukko.
（みお）遅いよ ゆっこ
もう 昼休み終わりそうじゃん
Lunch break is about to end.
Sorry.
ごめん ごめん
いやあ 買いに行くとき―
On the way,
I had to chase down a car and a dog to get my shoes back.
車と犬に靴 持っていかれて
追っかけるの大変だったから
（みお）うぎっ
I don't really know the whole story, but that sounds serious.
なんだか
よく話が見えないけど―
とにかく すごい事件みたいね
Well, the product was safely recovered.
まあ でも無事に届いて
何よりですよ
あれ？ ゆっこのお昼は？
Huh? Where's your lunch?
（祐子）
ん？ 歩きながら食べてきた
I ate it on my way here.
Oh, what did you eat?
（みお）へえ　何食べたの？
ホイコーロー弁当
Twice-cooked pork.
（みお）すごっ！
Whoa!
Twice-coo- Oh well, I guess it's okay.
ホイコーって…
まあ いっか
えっと…
Hey, Nano-chan, want to come eat with us?
じゃあ なのちゃん
こっちで一緒に食べない？
Huh?
Tell us more about yourself.
いろいろ なのちゃんのこと
教えてよ
Okay.
I wonder if they think I'm a normal kid.
（なの）
私のこと 普通の子って
思っているのかな？
Is it possible that they want to become friends?
も… もしかしたら 友達に
Hey, that thing on your back, Nano-chan...
ねえ　なのちゃんの
背中のそれって
えっ！ あげっ あ…
こっ これは 決して
怪しい物ではなくて その
This is definitely not anything strange...
It's like you're a robot!
もしかして なのちゃんって
ロボットだったりして！
No!
（なの）がーん！
What kind of stupid things are you saying?
（みお）
もう 何バカなこと言ってんの？
Sorry, Yukko is an idiot.
ごめんね　ゆっこバカだから
Oh, we don't have much time.
あっ もう時間ないや
Nano-chan, sorry. I guess we have to eat quickly.
なのちゃん ごめん
今日はパパッと食べちゃおうか？
Let's see.
さてと
Hey, Yukko.
ねえ ゆっこ　これって…
This is...
（祐子）ん？ 焼きサバだよ
It's fried mackerel.
But what I ordered was...
私が頼んだのって…
え？ 焼きサバでしょ？
Yeah, fried mackerel, right?
It was fried noodles!
焼きそばだよ！
あっ あちゃあ
Maybe I misheard you?
もしかして
聞き間違えちゃった？
メンゴ メンゴ
Please forgive me.
This isn't that cute of a problem!
そんな カワイイレベルの
問題じゃないよ！
ゆゆしき問題だよ！
It's a serious problem!
そう？ 似てるじゃん
だって １文字しか違わないし
Yeah, they're pretty similar.
TL note: "Saba" - "Mackerel", and "Soba" - "Noodles"
There's only a one-letter difference.
Even so...
だからって！ ああ
This will just have to do...
もういいよ　これで
…で ご飯は？
Where's the rice?
Hm? What do you mean?
（祐子）ん？ どうゆうこと？
I'm talking about white rice!
白飯だよ！
Oh, that's all there is.
え？ いや そんだけだけど
How am I supposed to eat this on its own?!
単品で どうやって食べんのよ！
ええ？ いや だって―
But you're the one who asked for fried mackerel.
みおちゃんが
焼きサバって言ったから
I said fried noodles!
焼きそばだよ！
I said...
焼いた！ そば！
...fried...
だよ！
...noodles!
Oh, I see!
そ… そっか そっか
This is the kind of thing you could use as material for your blog!
あっ でも ほら
こういう事件も―
ブログに書いて
ネタとして消費すれば
I don't have a computer!
コンピューター
持ってないよ！
（みお）うううっ
（祐子）もう
Geez!
（祐子）そんな
ポテンシャル上げて怒らなくても
You don't have to get so worked up.
分かったよ
I'll go buy it again, just give me money.
今からまた 買ってくるから
おカネおくれ
Why do I have to pay again?!
なんで私が また出すのよ！
That's because I don't have any money.
だって私 おカネないし
あっ もういいよ
分かったから早く買ってきて
Fine, just hurry up and go buy it for me.
昼休み終わっちゃうよ
Lunch is about to end.
Okay, okay!
（祐子）オーケー オーケー
Nothing but...
（みお）…しか ないよ
（祐子）え？
I have nothing but a peso!
ペソしかないよ！
I have nothing but a peso from Argentina that I was keeping as a souvenir.
前に 記念にと思って
とっておいた―
アルゼンチンペソしかないよ
What?
An Argentinian peso!
アルゼンチン！
ペソしかないよ！
Argentinian peso?
（祐子）
アルゼンチン ペソ
Besides, Yukko, you made the mistake, so you should pay!
大体 ゆっこが間違えたんだから
ゆっこが おカネ出してよね！
But I used up all my money buying my own lunch-
（祐子）だから 私は自分の
お弁当買って おカネなくな…
じゃあ 私のお昼 どうすんのよ！
Then what am I supposed to do with my lunch?!
え… えっと
Um, well...
じゃあ サバで！
How about the mackerel?
Mackerel?!
サバーッ！
（みお）もう！
（なの）サバ？
Mackerel?
I've always been annoyed by you.
（みお）大体 前から ゆっこには
イライラしてたのよ！
You're always asking me to show you my homework.
毎回 毎回
人の宿題写してさ―
Why don't you do it on your own for once, you idiot?!
少しは自分でやってきたら
どうなの？
このバカ！
Isn't my being an idiot completely
unrelated to you not having any lunch?
私がバカなのと みおちゃんが
お昼食べれないのは―
全然関係なくない？
It's completely related!
（みお）全然関係あるよ！
何！ 言ってみてよ！
Then tell me how!
You misheard it because you're an idiot!
バカだから
聞き間違えたんでしょ！
Huh?!
（祐子）ああ！
（みお）ふんっ！
Hey, everyone mishears things!
…つうか 聞き間違いぐらい
誰にだってあるでしょ？
それを ネチネチ ネチネチ
心が狭いよ！
You're so cold-hearted, nagging me about it!
Not having a lunch is a life or death situation!
（みお）こっちは
朝ごはん食べてないし―
死活問題なのよ！
But I guess an idiot can't understand that!
バカには分かんない
でしょうけどね！
バカじゃないし！
I'm not an idiot!
You admitted that you were a moron earlier!
（みお）さっき 自分で
バカって認めたでしょ？
言っとくけど
今度から ゆっこには―
I'll never show you my homework again!
絶対 宿題見せてやんないから！
That's fine!
はいはい 結構 結構！
But I won't let you copy my homework if you forget yours.
みおちゃんが忘れてきても
写させてあげないから
Who would want your crappy homework?!
（みお）誰が あんたの
お粗末な宿題見るってのよ！
Besides, you mistook my order, and you haven't even apologised!
大体 間違って買ってきて
謝りのひとつもないの？
Bow down to me!
土下座しなさいよ！ 土下座！
All right.
If I bow down to you, is it all right?
土下座すりゃあいいんでしょ
土下座すりゃあ！
I'm extremely sorry to have caused you inconvenience!
はい どーも
すみませんでした！
There, I apologised!
ほれ！ 謝った！
Is that all right?
これでいいでしょ！ これで！
はあ？ それ
土下座じゃないでしょ！
That's not bowing down!
That's right.
ああ そうだよ 土下座じゃないよ
前屈だよ！ 前屈！
It wasn't. I was just bending forward!
Why won't you bow down to me?
なんで土下座しないのよ！
（祐子）キレてるからだよ！
It's because I've snapped!
Besides, you're the moron, Mio-chan.
…つうか みおちゃんこそ
バカなんじゃないの？
What were those strange drawings?
何？ この前の
あの 変なイラスト！
Oh.
（みお）
あ… あの 変なイラスト
Those strange drawings...
ア… アホか　あれは…
Stupid! Those were...
What were those drawings?
（祐子）何あのイラスト
意味分かんないし
I don't get them!
They were weird! Very odd!
分かるように描けだし
眼鏡だし
Are you an idiot?!
（みお）アホか！
（祐子）ああっ！
Are you an idiot, idiot, idiot?!
アホか アホか アホか！
What are you saying?
（祐子）何よそれ！
You're the idiot that did those idiotic drawings, aren't you?!
アホみたいなイラスト描いてる
あんたがアホでしょ？
（みお）はぐ！
（祐子）
ほら とっとと食べちゃいな
あんたが頼んだ焼きサバだよ！
Here, why don't you just hurry up and eat the fried mackerel you ordered?!
I ordered fried noodles!
焼きそばだろうが！
Bow down to me and apologise!
土下座で謝れ！
こうべを深々と垂れて！
Hang your head low!
（祐子）買ってきちゃったもんは
しょうがないでしょ
I've already bought it, so I can't do anything about it!
Be a human being and apologise, you worthless person!
人として謝れよ
このカス人間！
All right, then!
（祐子）分かったよ
I'll show you!
見せてやるよ
本当の土下座を！
A true bow!
This is a true bow!
これが 本当の
土下座じゃあ！
（みお）くうっ
Where is your apology for the fried mackerel?
“焼きサバで
すみませんでした”は？
You're supposed to apologise when you bow!
土下座したら謝罪でしょうが！
Say that you're sorry for getting me fried mackerel!
ほら 言えよ！
“焼きサバで
すみませんでした”って！
Hurry up and say it!
さあ 早く言いなさいよ
“バカですみませんでした”って！
Say that you're sorry for being a moron!
Say it from the pits of your heart,
心から謝れよ！
このカス人間！
you scum of a human!
Come on! Hurry up!
ほら  早く！
さっさと言え バカ！
Say it already, you moron!
Apologise already, you idiot!
早く謝れボケ！
Scum! Idiot! Moron!
カス！ アホ！ バカ！
うおりゃ！
（中之条 剛(なかのじょうつよし)）ああっ！
くっ もう！ バカバカ
うるさいんだよ みおちゃんは！
Geez!
You're so annoying with all the "morons"!
What do you know about me after only knowing me for half a year?!
半年や そこらのつきあいで
私の何が分かるっていうの！
Same goes for you!
あんただって
私の絵の何が分かるっていうの？
What do you understand about my drawings?!
I do understand!
分かるよ！
そんな絵がウマかったら
マンガ家にでもなればいいでしょ！
You're so good at drawing,
so why don't you just become a manga artist?!
What are you saying?
な… 何言ってんの？
バッカじゃないの
Are you a moron?
Huh?
はあ？ バカって言ったほうが
バカでしょ　この バカ！
The one who says "moron" is the moron, you moron!
Didn't you yourself say "moron"?
自分でバカって言ったんじゃない
（祐子）言ってないよ！
I did not!
Yes, you did!
言ったよ！
But I don't dislike that part of you.
でも あんたのそういうとこ―
嫌いじゃないけど
は… はあ？ 何言ってんの？
頭いいくせに！
What are you talking about?
Even though you're so smart...
う… うるさいわね
この 笑顔の天才
Shut up, you... comedic genius.
What are you talking about?
な… 何よ そっちこそ
絵がウマいくせに！
Even though you're so good at drawing...
Shut up!
うるさい！ 足速いくせに！
You're such a fast runner.
You're really smart!
頭いいくせに！
（みお）プラス思考のくせに！
You're an optimist!
You're really smart!
頭いいくせに！
You're actually pretty smart!
（みお）逆に 頭いいくせに！
（みお･祐子）うんん…
（なの）
はああっ　すごーい
That's amazing!
Go Soccer Club
A Tale of Go
Stones and Balls
Adolescence
Go Soccer Club
A Tale of Go
Stones and Balls
（高崎(たかさき)先生）フッ
Senpai, this is so frustrating!
（高崎）先輩　俺 悔しいっす
Don't cry!
（先輩）
泣くな  お前には来年がある
You still have next year.
I'll definitely win for you!
（高崎）必ず 先輩の分まで
Yeah!
よっしゃあ！
That was in the past.
（高崎）昔のことだ
Hey, Nano, was school fun?
（はかせ）ねえねえ なの
学校 面白かった？
Well, let's see...
（なの）そうですねえ
いろいろありましたけど―
A lot of things happened, but how do I say it...
何というか…
Say it? Say it?
何というか？ 何というか？
友達って すごいなって思いました
I thought that friends are really amazing!
わああっ それはすごい
That's awesome!
Hey, I don't get it.
（阪本）コラコラ
わけ分かんねえぞ
うっ！ ううっ どおっ
（なの）ほお はあっ！
Professor!
（なの）はかせ！
（はかせ）なに？
Yes?
Please remove this key on my back!
背中のネジ 取ってください！
ダメ
No.
（なの）な… なんでですか？
Why is that?
It causes a lot of problems at school!
学校生活に
いろいろ支障があるんです
Today, someone thought that I was a robot!
今日だって
ロボだって疑われたんですよ
これじゃあ 友達できないですよ
I can't make any friends this way.
（はかせ）
できるよ カワイイから
Yes, you can, because you're cute.
（なの）カワイくないです！
No, I'm not cute!
The key is cute.
（はかせ）カワイイよ ネジ
Let's hurry up and eat.
（阪本）
いいから早く メシにしようぜ
（なの）はかせ！
Professor!
I'm a soccer ball.
I'm always being kicked, kicked, kick-kicked around everywhere!
And then, I sleep!
The next episode is Nichijou 15.
Narration:     Chiba Shigeru
Be prepared!
（サッカーボール）
サッカーボールです
蹴って 蹴って 蹴られて蹴って
蹴って 蹴り潰れて
しぼむだけって…
そして 眠るのです
次回の「日常」は
第15話です
お楽しみに